Patricia Castillo

Core Skill:

Data Analyst

Industry Verticals:

Capital Markets Insurance

Programming Languages:

T-SQL C# C++ PL/SOL

Databases:

Microsoft SQL Server MySQL Oracle

Tools & Techniques:

GitHub Tableau Logi Analytics

SQL Scrum DBT Snowflake

Summary:

System Engineer with high desires to bring all skills and effort where can grow new projects by means of all experience about analysis, design, installation, testing and maintenance of Software Systems. Knowledge about SQL Server Analysis, Development and Management. PL-300 Power BI Data Analyst Associate.

Qualifications:

Educational Background:

System Engineer, ITM – Medellin, 2015

Certifications:

Data Analysis with Power BI , Platzi, 2022 Tableau: Data Visualization and Storytelling for business , Platzi, 2022 Power BI Data Analysis Associate , Microsoft, 2022 Professional Curse Scrum , Platzi, 2021

Spoken Languages:

English, B1+

Soft Skills:

Adaptability
Analysis
Autodidact
Collaborative
Critical Thinking
Ethical thinking
Hardworking
Persistence
Proactivity
Reliability
Team Work

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Industry sector: Finan	ce	
Data Analyst		
2023-08-01 - Currently	/	
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:	
Building reports on Tableau according to end-user's requirements.	Collecting and interpreting data • Analysing results • Reporting the results back to the relevant members of the business • Working alongside teams within the business or the management team to establish business needs • Defining new data collection and analysis processes • Working with Tableau tool, DBT software and snowflake.	
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:
T-SQL		

Industry sector: Insurance		
Data Analyst		
2022-11-01 – 2023-06-30		
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:	
Collecting and interpreting data • Analysing results • Reporting the results back to the relevant members of the business • Working alongside teams within the business or the management team to establish business needs • Defining new data collection and analysis processes	Understanding of data and data flows. Their systems integration and specialized tools for data extraction, ingestion, validation, cleaning processing.	
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:
PL/SQL		

Industry sector: IT Services		
Project Leader		
2020-01-01 - 2022-01-19		
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:	
Attend the projects in charge around the country.	Team Leadership, staff management. • Testing UAT. • Product Owner. • Scrum master. • SQL development (SP, functions, triggers) • Work as part of an Agile Methodology POD (SCRUM)	
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:
T-SQL, SQL	SQL, Sql Server, Sql developer	

Industry sector: IT Services			
Project Leader			
2017-01-01 – 2021-01-01			
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:		
Attend the projects in charge around the country, analysis and design the artefacts to deploy and maintenance the projects.	Windows Server Management. • Staff management. Worked with SQL Server, SQL Server and SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) - ETL. • Deployment of Tasks scheduled. • Performed Transact SQL (T-SQL) with hands-in troubleshooting complex stored –procedures, functions, cursors.		
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:	
T-SQL, SQL	Sql Server, Sql developer		

Industry sector: IT Services			
Project Leader			
2005-01-01 – 2017-01-01			
Project descriptions:	Responsibilities:		
Planning projects in charge around the country, analysis and design the artefacts to deploy and maintenance the projects.	Team leadership, staff management • Develop solutions from SQL databases based on specifications and technical designs by means of T-SQL (Store procedures, functions, cursors) • Analysis, design and develop of solutions for system projects about documental management. • Advanced Excel. • KPIs control, production control.		
Programming Languages:	Tools & Techniques:	Testing:	
T-SQL, SQL	Sql Server, Visual Studio Code		